

SHALINI SHARMA

Full Stack Web Developer

CONTACT DETAILS:

Email: shalini07061997@gmail.com

Mobile: 8707568618

Location: Noida, Uttar Pradesh
Portfolio: https://isnt-00shalini-

awesome.netlify.app/

LinkedIn: shalini-sharma-8b0466163/

GitHub: 00shalini

SUMMARY

Proficient in MERN Stack and solving DS and algorithm problems, with experience in developing collaborative as well as independent projects. Highly interested to take responsibilities as a Full Stack Web Developer in an IT company and achieve organizational objectives through my skill set and dedication.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Html | CSS | JavaScript | React | Working with API | Postman | Writing Testcases | Material UI | working with Libraries | Data Structures & algorithms | MongoDB | Express | Canvas | Socket.io | Redux | Java | SpringBoot

SOFT SKILLS

- Quick Learner
- Time Management
- Result Oriented.
- · Optimism
- Remote collaboration

PAST EXPERIENCE

Jr Software Developer

Full Creative

Oct, 2021 - Mar, 2022 | Chennai , Tamil Nadu Area of Work:

- Front End Development in Form Creator Team.
- Added Functionalities for forms based on time limit.

Intern, Web developer MKT Softwares Pvt. Ltd.

Mar, 2020 - Jun, 2020 | Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh

Area of Work:

- Recieved project training on Wordpress Framework.
- Redesigned the webpages and acquired experience in inter-department coordination

EDUCATION

• Full Stack Web Development (Full Time)

Masai School

Jan 2021 - 2022 | Remote

• Masters in Computer Application

Jagran Institute of Management (Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam University)

Aug 2018 - May 2020 | Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh

· Bachelors in Computer Application

Kanpur University Jul 2015 - Sep 2018 | Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh

PROJECTS

TutorTown (Hackathon)

A website that provides job for tutors and tutors for students.

• Teck Stack Used:

React, Redux, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Socket.io, WebRTC, Styled Components, Mongoose, RazorPay, Libraries (Material UI)

- Duration: 2 Weeks
- Responsibilities:

Implemented live chat functionality using socket.io for group conversations.

Pepperfry Website

An E-Commerce website that sells Home- Decor and Furniture.

• Teck Stack Used:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Firebase, Styled Components, Mongoose, RazorPay, Libraries (Ant Design, Material UI, and Bootstrap)

- Duration: 2 Weeks
- Responsibilities:

Implemented the footer, checkout functionality, and carousals. Merge the code on Github

• Additional features: Created API for the website.

Rodan & Fields Website

An E-Commerce website that sells skincare products.

Teck Stack Used:

- HTML CSS, JavaScript, DOM Manipulation
- Duration: 3 Days
- Responsibilities:

Implemented Navbar, footer, the home page, header. Merge the code on Github.

ACTIVITIES

- Participated in Masai Hackathon Developed a collaborative project (TutorTown). Secured 2nd position among 16 teams.
- Blogs writing.
- Competing in coding platforms such as (Hackerrank, Leetcode)
- Earning assessment badges on Linkedin